ALEX DULAC

APPLICATION DEVELOPER

• Westbrook, Maine

github.com/alex-dulac

ABOUT ME

Application developer with over 4 years of professional experience in full stack web app development. I seek continuous improvement in both myself and the projects that I work on. I'm passionate about learning, collaboration, and writing clean code. It is important to me that I work on projects I find meaningful. My goal is to not only solve problems and bring ideas to reality, but also provide a great user experience via the entire stack.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Application Developer

September 2018 - Present

IDEXX Laboratories Westbrook, Maine

- Full stack application developer of a veterinary practice management system for an S&P 500 company.
- Plan, design, and develop new features, from kickoff to delivery.
- Support, update and maintain existing systems as needed.
- Submit code reviews & approvals for teammates.
- Ensure seamless communication to applicable parties for various application issues as needed by translating technical problems into easy-to-understand solutions.
- Directly involved in all steps of the complete reconstruction of an essential feature of the application, from legacy JavaScript and jQuery to Angular with TypeScript and NgRx. This feature saved veterinary practices an average of 4 minutes per clinic visit.

Health Data Analyst

July 2017 - August 2018

Onpoint Health Data Portland, Maine

- Investigated and addressed data issues that arose in delivering data integration and analytic services.
- Performed in-depth and ad-hoc analyses, code testing, and routine quality assurance activities.

Advertising Review Principal

March 2015 - April 2017

Foreside Financial Group Portland, Maine

- Earned FINRA Series 7 (stockbroker) and FINRA Series 24 (supervisor of broker-dealer activities) certifications.
- Reviewed and approved clients' ETF and mutual fund marketing materials to ensure compliance with current regulatory standards.

SKILLS

Languages

PHP, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, Java, HTML/CSS, Python

Frameworks

PHP: Laravel, Doctrine, Symfony JS: Angular, React, Node.js

Java: Spring

Databases

MySQL, Oracle

Tools

Docker, AWS (S3, RDS, EC2, SQS, Lambda), DataDog, Sentry, Github, Postman, PHPUnit, Selenium, Jenkins, Jira, Excel

Knowledge / Experience

Object-oriented methodologies and class design, API development, state management, relational database design, query optimization, proficient in debugging and troubleshooting

EDUCATION

University of Southern Maine

Bachelor of Arts, Communication and Marketing 2014